I
Speaker 1: love hugs.
This is
Speaker 1: amazing. Wow. Oh, everybody's just hugging. This is a vibe right now.
Speaker 2: amazing. Where's
my
Speaker 1: phone? Good thing
there's press
Speaker 1: here. Somebody's got that.
Guys, so
Woman 3: the next panel that we have is to really just do a deep dive on what's happening to the Latino community. This is going to be the first Lexit panel, and we're really excited to just really talk about what is actually happening to the Hispanic American
Woman 3: So we're just gonna get this off stage get some chairs up here. We've got two panels that are really important and then a big ending
Speaker 7: Let's go.
Speaker 8: I'll
see
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): you next
Speaker 10: time.
Speaker 10: First,
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): I'd just like
Speaker 11: to start off by saying, giving all the glory in God to my Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, who made all of this possible right now.
And
Speaker 12: also, as a Latino, I want to say that Acosta, Anna Navarro, and Jorge Ramos does not speak for
Speaker 14: Latinos. We don't own them. Adios, muchachos. All right,
so I guess the
Speaker 15: first question I have for you guys is, how has illegal immigration affected the Hispanic community?
So I'd
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): say for me personally, growing up in Los Angeles and personally seeing the effect that drugs has on the Hispanic community, in particular my family, I think that illegal immigration from that standpoint is probably the biggest issue. There is a correlated problem with open borders and drugs that are coming in that are not only affecting the Hispanic community, but all American communities that are...
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): essentially poor. And on top of that, why is there no media real coverage of what's happening with the human trafficking issue? I mean, even if we booked out a thousand people in this room
today,
Woman 17: imagine
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): this
entire room,
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): every single one of you a child, there are 16,000 children that have been victims of human trafficking at the U.S.-Mexico border. Now, it doesn't mean that there's not a problem here in the United States about that, that we shouldn't come down on these people like a sack of bricks, but this is children that are raped, tortured, sometimes murdered, and resold for profit. That's sick.
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): And it's our moral responsibility as Americans to take a stand against that, whether or not we are black, Hispanic, or
white. - Absolutely. And you
Speaker 18: know, when you get into illegal immigration, it's really about mobility too. So when these people come into our communities, they're primarily coming into communities where legal immigrants and black Americans live. That's where they're going to. And they're taking those opportunities, and those are the people who suffer, is our American citizens who are Hispanic,
Speaker 18: Latino, black, and those are the ones who suffer. So when you look at a state like Texas, where in the last seven years, 2,500 kids have been sexually abused, raped, whose kids are those? Those are those kids in those communities. Those are Hispanic kids that are being raped. Those
Speaker 19: are black Americans, and there's some white Americans too, but primarily when legal immigration is going into those places, it's creating victims in those places.
- So I guess what
Speaker 20: the real question has to be here is why is illegal immigration, why is it
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): continuing to be an issue? First of all, my name is Benito Bernal. I'm here on behalf of the Republican National Hispanic Assembly. In order for you guys to really understand my perspective,
For
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): the past 25 years, I was a strategist for the Democratic Party and the unions. I helped build the Latino political machine, which is all the leaders representing the state of California right now. It's actually politics 18 years ago that led me to become a Christian, to have a relationship with God Almighty instead of just religion. And that's what opened my eyes.
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): So why? The machine was put together because we're going to deal with issues of illegal immigration, the gang violence, the abuse in the welfare system. And here we have a question when you're talking about illegal immigration. The human trafficking, you hit it. They've known about the human trafficking for many years. I mean, even before I was involved, it's a serious issue where innocent women and children are being abducted and so do the human sex trade.
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): The problem with it right now is that there is the profit margin with the welfare system. There is money to be made, and that's why they don't want to solve the issue. We as Americans, we have to stand up together, and we have to put this to a stop, and we have a president that's willing
to
Speaker 22: do it. Donald Trump.
Speaker 23: Amen. The biggest ones that are affected is the minorities. The
Speaker 24: blacks and Latinos are the most ones affected by illegal immigration,
so...
Speaker 24: I go on with everything
Speaker 25: you guys are saying. The second one is, in your opinion,
what is the
Speaker 25: biggest issue that needs to be addressed in the Hispanic community? I
think right
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): now it's the issue of waking people up. What I've come to find on various campus tours that I've done with Turning Point is that there's so many people that have been brainwashed into thinking that if you are pro-American, if you have a pro-American stance on
Woman 17: immigration, you're racist. But hold on, are we all white in here? I mean, there's nothing wrong with being white, but aren't we minorities?
Woman 17: Aren't we people of all color and creed? So how are you going to tell me that I'm racist because I see a correlated issue with human trafficking? Because there's literally slavery taking place. They won't remind black Americans every single day that they were slaves at one point, and they turn a blind eye to the slavery of Hispanic women and children. They don't care about us.
Speaker 26: Absolutely. You know, I think that...
what we
Speaker 26: need to talk about is voting.
Speaker 18: Because Hispanics vote 20% less than black Americans or white Americans. And there's a disconnect there with Hispanic voting and their values. Because Hispanic values, you look at, let's take abortion, okay? On abortion, the number one group that wants abortion to be made illegal is Hispanics. They're over 50% margin. Foreign-born Hispanics that are legally immigrated are at 60%. So that group of people
Speaker 18: They're not voting Republican for some reason. And the reason is that the Democratic Party has been able to tell
Speaker 27: them and dictate for too long who we are, and it's not who we are. So we need to take the power and tell them who we are.
And we need
Speaker 27: to get out into their communities and we
need to get out
Speaker 27: into their communities
Speaker 27: and spend the time and that's where you get into what are we all gonna do after we leave here today and we have to turn this inspiration into action. So for the next two years, until 2020, until the day that Trump's elected again.
Until
Speaker 27: then, every one of us can be doing something, you know, whether it's posting on social media exposing the way the media has lied to people, you know, whether it's going out in your community, registering
Speaker 28: people to vote, or next time a Blexit, you know, tour comes through your town, bring a curious friend, bring two, you know, and challenge people who think that the Republican Party
Speaker 27: is racist,
Speaker 27: Challenge them to come here and listen, meet us, talk to us, and at the end of that day, ask them, do you think these people that you met are racist? They're not.
Nobody I'm
Speaker 27: looking at right now has acted like a racist today,
Speaker 29: you know?
So let me talk about a generation
Speaker 30 (higher-pitched voice): that's about to be lost in the next 10 years. You need to listen to what I'm saying here. Our parents that are in
Speaker 31: their 70s, 80s, and some in their early 90s, Democrats, very
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): conservative, very conservative
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): values. Why do they...
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): continue to vote for Democrats. The Spanish media, the monolingual speakers, Hispanic speakers, don't have an outlet. They have Univision,
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): they have Telemundo. It is up to us, exactly, it is up to us to try to create some type of a Spanish outlet so that we can give them the
Speaker 34: facts and give them the truth and let them know exactly where this party stands because Republicans are conservatives.
Exactly. A
Speaker 24: lot of people don't know that, but the Spanish channels are just as bad as fake new CNN and the Spanish channel is just a propaganda for the Democratic Party. And also, like they were saying is, we need to put God back because Blacks and Latinos, we have Godly moral values. We've got to start voting our conscience. We've got to start voting our Godly values.
And so
Speaker 35: the
Speaker 15: third question is, has the Democratic Party hurt the Hispanic community? Say
again? Has
Speaker 15: the Democratic Party hurt the Hispanic community in regards to
Speaker 36: illegal immigration? I think
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): the Democratic Party has absolutely hurt the Hispanic community in regards to illegal immigration. And in fact, for 15 years, politicians, professional politicians, have done nothing on immigration. They've left it as a festering wound. they've stuck a big fat Band-Aid on it
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): include the DACA program, which didn't help anyone, and they left us to deal with it. And frankly, at the end of the day, when you're looking at the stats and what the reason why this is even an issue to begin with, if you go to pewhispanic.org, you have the largest voting minority here in the United States as Hispanic Americans, specifically Mexican Americans. So why is it in the media when you hear the term illegal, you all of a sudden think
of
Woman 17: Mexican?
Woman 17: There's more illegals that are Russian, Chinese, from all around the world. It is not just Mexicans. They are trying to turn us into single issue voters, and you cannot have our vote. As long as Candace Owens is here, as long as I'm here, and as long as all of you are here,
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): they will never take our
vote. You
Speaker 38: know, what I found really rich is watching people like Nancy Pelosi calling a wall.
Speaker 38: You could boo a little louder for her, come on. There you go, no. But watching people like her call a wall immoral, okay? Immorality, what's immoral is
Speaker 39 (higher-pitched voice): that people like Nancy Pelosi and Chuck Schumer have been in our government in high level positions for how long now? Decades, decades, and they've done nothing, nothing. While people die,
Speaker 39 (higher-pitched voice): kids have been raped they've done nothing that's immoral
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): immoral is giving a child plan B contraceptives because they're going
Woman 17: to be raped on the journey over here and then saying that you want to abolish ICE the very agency that's sitting here and combating human trafficking at the US Mexico border Nancy Pelosi is the biggest hypocrite on the face
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): of the planet Ocasio-Cortez the biggest hypocrite on the face of the
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): planet
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): Let's set the record straight.
First of
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): all, the Democratic Party for many, many, many years opposed illegal immigration.
Why did that change? I'm going
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): to tell you why. So now you see the current Secretary of State, Alex Padilla, and many others who are pushing for illegal immigrants for the right to vote. You want to know why that is?
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): Because first and second generation American citizens are educated now. We know that the political game is a bunch of political propaganda and all
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): it is is about money and power. So it's time for us to change that and change the mindset of all these people
that are
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): here in America.
I also think that
Speaker 24: identity politics is what the Democrats are using. They like to play minorities for votes.
Speaker 24: They like everything. If you watch the fake news media or you listen to them, everything is about race. Everything is racist, racist, everything. Anytime you argue with the liberal or whatever it is, it always is race, race, race, race, every time. That's what they always try to do. They just use race to manipulate minorities. And that's why I wanted to found Lexit and then us in the Republican National Hispanic Assembly. We're tired of it. We're trying to reach the Latino community.
Speaker 40: - That's right. Make this happen.
Speaker 40: make it happen.
The next
Speaker 15: question is, why is it important
Speaker 25: to support legal immigration and denounce illegal immigration?
First
Woman 17: and foremost, because I'd have to say there's over 4 million people that are waiting to come here legally. How is it fair that you have someone literally jumping a border to come here? And by the way, hold up. We are the United States of America. We you're not part of Mexico, it is okay for us
to
Woman 17: have a defined border. There's nothing wrong with taking a pro-American stance on immigration. So regardless of your skin color, we stay here backing legal immigration because we see the problems correlated with human trafficking, the drug running. I mean, I have Jesse sitting right here if you want to tell them your story real quick about how you ended up in that wheelchair. But there is an issue with gang violence affecting our communities,
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): the drug pouring into our communities. It is our responsibility to take a stand against all of this. And if you want to Tell them about your story. -
Speaker 24: Yeah, I'm an ex gang member from right here
Speaker 24: California and we all know that all the drugs coming through that's why, why are the Democrats against the wall? I mean why? Look at how many people died, look at all the deaths from drugs everything, like me, I got shot from gang
Speaker 12: violence, everything but now I use that for God's glory So,
you
Speaker 26: know, what I would say about
the
Speaker 26: importance of legal immigration is
Speaker 18: that you let's go back to what Larry Elder said earlier he said hard work
wins all
Speaker 18: okay anybody that's on the list to come here legally
Speaker 41: they have a desire to work hard okay so I'll tell you a little story I'm I'm the son of a Cuban immigrant my mom came
Speaker 42: here legally and Cubans if you don't know already are the best
Speaker 27: Hispanics because they're the most conservative
You
Speaker 27: know, not knocking anybody else, but it is it is true. She'll admit it too. I mean, we're the best. We're
Speaker 43: gonna file it
Speaker 27: Yeah, it's true. We we vote Republican so we have work to do on the other ones, but see we've got our heads on straight and the reason why
is
Speaker 27: because our families experienced communism. They experienced socialism. And when they came here, my great-grandpa had already built a life in Cuba, and he was a businessman, he had this great job, and he had employees, he took care of people. When he came here, he was a
Speaker 28: janitor that only knew Spanish.
Speaker 28: and he worked his way up from being a janitor and I never heard him complain about it. In fact, the only thing I ever heard from him was
Speaker 42: a value for the American dream and being thankful that the United States was here to come to.
I
Speaker 44: said in the beginning, I wasn't going to repeat once it's already been said, so they pretty much
Speaker 30 (higher-pitched voice): covered what had to be said. But at the end of the day, you know, this is a serious issue. You know, we all have to stand up, come together, and we have to just, like my brother shared earlier, we have to share this message with everyone, our families, our friends. The message, the truth, the facts have
Speaker 45: to get out there. So once again, it's going to be up to us to get that done.
I just want
Speaker 46: to
Speaker 24: keep encouraging everybody to do your homework and then just be wary of the fake news media. Like Trump said, they're truly the enemies of America. It's the fake news left arm
Speaker 15: of the left Democratic Party. I just want to say one
Speaker 30 (higher-pitched voice): more thing. Has anybody here taken the time to read the Constitution of Mexico?
their
Speaker 30 (higher-pitched voice): immigration
Speaker 47: policies are even tougher than here in the United States. Take some time
Speaker 15: to read it.
Do you
Speaker 15: believe the Democratic Party has been divisive within the Hispanic community? They've
Speaker 48: been divisive in the American community. I mean, look at what they're doing right now.
Speaker 48: Absolutely. In
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): fact, I think one of the most hurtful things that I constantly hear when I'm talking to younger kids and younger students is the fact that sometimes their family members will disown them. There's literally fights. I mean, I have my own sister right now. She's not talking to me because apparently I'm posting offensive stuff, but my stuff's not offensive. I mean, how is human trafficking offensive? How is what's going on at the border offensive? But you have this happening on a regular basis, and it's literally causing the family to divide.
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): And I think in talking to you earlier, talking about the welfare state, how the welfare programs will come in and create these destabilized family structures so that they can have a government, basically relationship, right? And have a big brother come in and take care of you. That's absolutely a problem that I think that they're doing not only just to Hispanics, but to all Americans.
-
Speaker 49: Absolutely. You know, it's hard to follow her up. I feel like she hits everything and then we're just trying to play catch-up.
Speaker 50: I'll shut up, guys. - No, she does on our
Speaker 18: show. - No,
but,
Speaker 18: Seriously, you know there she's right. They're divisive in every community
Speaker 41: I don't want to localize it too much to how divisive they are in the Hispanic or Latino community because what they're doing there is what they're doing everywhere It's just different levels and different types of manipulation, you know So in each community they have their own way to manipulate you into believing what you should do and let me give you an example, so
Speaker 18: 29% of Hispanics voted for Trump 2016 okay today
After
Speaker 18: all of that, media manipulation has started to wear off because they've lived through a couple years of his presidency. His approval rate with Hispanics is higher than whites or black Americans.
Speaker 28: It's at 51 percent, okay, yeah, and at this same time, President Obama was at
Speaker 27: 49 percent. So he's outperforming President Obama, and that is not a right-wing poll, that is NPR,
Speaker 27: That is NPR, and it's another left-wing site that's not worth anything, but they
Speaker 41: obviously, they tend to skew their poles that way, you know, so, but I'll give you another example, working in Hollywood, I'm a director, you know, if you don't know me, my name's Robbie Starbuck, I've worked with people like Natalie Portman, Snoop Dogg, you know, it goes down the
list.
Speaker 41: And I know I boo some of them too, but I try to keep politics out of that side of my job, but you can't always do that, and I've actually had a film studio come to me that wanted to hire me for a job, they hired me, they come back and they say, "We're sorry, we have to hire
Speaker 18: a black director."
And
Speaker 18: I was like, okay, could you kind of expand on that? Is there a reason why? And they were like,
oh, we just,
Speaker 18: we need that representation on this project. And I said, okay, well, I'm Cuban. And
Speaker 28: they go, oh, we didn't know that. Let us check with the talent and we'll get back to you. And they check, they come back and they were like, yeah, but you are Republican. And that actually happened.
Speaker 28: So, being Republican and being outward about it and not being ashamed to tell people what I
Speaker 41: believe, you know, apparently you can do that if you're on that side, but you're not allowed to do it on this side. So, you know, it just gives you another example.
Speaker 42: Every layer of life, from the
very, you know, core of
Speaker 42: where kids are growing up in elementary school, all the way up into the work world, their divisiveness reigns supreme throughout all of it, you know. And the more we get people to wake up to that,
the better. As I shared with you
Speaker 31: guys when I first came out here,
I
Speaker 31: was a strategist for the Democratic Party and the unions, right? But this was not a part of my strategy. When you talk about illegal immigration, when you talk about the abuse in the welfare system, that was part
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): of their plan.
The plan was
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): to destroy the family foundation. Because once you destroy the family foundation, what do you have? You have children running around being educated by the public system that is then brainwashing them like many of us were brainwashed in the Chicano movement, in the Raza movement, right? It's the same
thing.
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): that's going on. So when I started seeing that this was your strategy
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): to destroy the Family Foundation, that's when I dropped to my knees and I said, "Lord, I need direction because this
is not
Speaker 33 (higher-pitched voice): where I'm supposed to be." But the Lord said, "No, you're going to stay there because you're going to be the voice and you're going to up and coming leaders. You're going to tell them what's really going on." So it's not by coincidence. It's part of their
plan. Another thing that I noticed
Speaker 12: about the Democratic
Speaker 24: Party is they're the party of hate.
Speaker 24: they're so hateful imagine me i'm a mexican in a wheelchair
and i
Speaker 24: have to think twice about wearing my a trump hat outside because i'm i could get attacked or just something that shouldn't be because somebody's a
Speaker 12: democrat or even they voted for obama or whoever i don't care doesn't bother me none but see them they're not like that they're hateful say the most disrespectful even racist things to me and that's why they always claim racist the most racist that i've seen is from them
liberals
And also,
Speaker 12: another thing, they always try to make it seem like Latinos are for open borders and all that. We're not. Hell no. No! No!
Speaker 52: We're
Speaker 53: all Latinos right here. We all -- what
Speaker 52: do you guys feel
Speaker 53: -- the
Speaker 12: next question is
Speaker 53: about the wall. This A, fake news. We're all Latinos right here. We want the wall. News flash.
Yes.
Build
Speaker 54: the wall,
Speaker 55: build the wall, build the wall, build the wall, build
the wall. How do you
Speaker 56: feel about the
Speaker 57: wall, Anna?
Speaker 50: I'm all fine. I don't know if you guys saw my commercial I did, but I'd go down there and
help build
Speaker 50: it if I could.
Speaker 57: Ten feet taller. Go
Speaker 50: ahead. Call the National Guard. I'll
Woman 17: be
there.
- How do you
Speaker 23: feel about the wall? How do you feel about the wall? Are you a favor for the
wall?
Speaker 58: - Absolutely. I
Speaker 27: mean, the wall is, you look at, so let's talk about the things they say to us about the wall. They say somebody can go
Speaker 28: over it or under it, okay? You know, so let's answer the question for them. They keep calling it medieval, so teach them about drone capture technology.
Speaker 28: Give us the money, Nancy. Nancy Pelosi, give us the money. We'll put drone capture technology on top and we'll put tunnel detection technology on the bottom. OK, so it solves that problem. Now, let's look at the Yuma section of the border where we do have a border wall. Illegal immigration there has been cut in 90 percent, 90 percent. So only 10 percent of what it was before we had a wall there. And in Israel, where they have a completed wall, because the only reason we have a trickle there. There you go.
Speaker 28: In Israel, 99%, 99% effective their wall, okay? 99% effective. And
we support
Speaker 59: Israel, don't we?
Okay, I know we've got
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): to wrap it up. We've got to wrap it up, so let me just end with this. When you talk to those who oppose the wall, I'm going to share a story with you when I was running for Congress just a couple of years ago. A father who was bringing his wife and his two children, four-year-old and five-year-old,
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): When they got to the border
at
Speaker 21 (higher-pitched voice): Tijuana, they were separated. The women from the, the women and children from the men. They were put in separate vehicles and sent to separate homes. The men were given a backpack. They were forced to smuggle drugs into this country. They were given a number. They said, once you get these
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): drugs into the country, you get your family back. Guess what happened? This father, once he did that, called that number, never found his wife or his four-year-old or his five-year-old daughter. They were sold into the human sex trade. When you share that story with people, these people who are opposing us
Speaker 32 (higher-pitched voice): They break down into tears because they know it's real. So let's get the right message out there.
No more slavery
Speaker 60: in America. Thank
Speaker 61: you. God bless you. God bless America. God first. Keep God the center of it all.
Speaker 62 (lower-pitched voice): We'll be right back.